no WF PLS pleas uh I don't know I feel
like it should be plz plz I think you're
stuck in 2012 bro I don't
know nobody says plz anymore does no say
plz am I showing my Millennial here okay
yeah you're old you're old dude outdated
[Music]
[Applause]
hey everyone this is techn geek here
just wanted to give a quick shout out to
our latest sponsor project Discovery now
project Discovery makes a lot of tools
that you probably know of or have even
used uh one of them is nuclei and the
latest release of nuclei is version 3.2
now 3.2 comes with a lot of really
awesome new features um two I really
wanted to highlight here for you are the
authenticated scanning and the advanced
fuzzing support now for authenticated
scanning it used to be that you would
have to do all your nuclei scanning
against unauthenticated end points or
you'd have to add your cookies manually
all that kind of messy no more it's all
automatic you can use existing login
templates to automatically log to your
application and then you can run all
your existing nuclei templates against
an authenticated part of the application
now to really increase your coverage uh
the the other that I mentioned is
Advanced fuzzing support now nuclea had
added way back in version 2.8 the
ability to fuzz different things but now
they've expanded this comprehensively
across the board so not only can you
fuzz in the normal spots but you can
fuzz within headers you can fuzz within
cookies you can fuzz within specific
parts of the body whether that's in Json
or XML or form data and so many more
things so if you want to learn more
about what came in nuclei 3.2 go ahead
and check out the the release blog post
over at nu. g/p podcast that's
n.p podcast
thanks all right Joel how are you
feeling about these bad boys right here
those I mean it matches your eyes man
it's good what do you mean it matches my
eyes they're bright pink I uh I left I
left for those of you listening I left
my headphones in the car this week and I
don't have them right now so I stole my
wife's bright pink Bose headphones right
now that I'm doing this pod with so um
you know the devotion the Devotion to
the Pod am I right very very stylish
very stylish thank you thank you very
much man that that aamc con weekend that
was a blast dude yeah that was super
awesome um it uh I don't think many
people would think that we sort of threw
that together last minute but uh yeah
that was uh very uh on the on the Fly uh
sort of setup that we had going on there
it looked great uh through the camera
behind it was just like chaos chaos well
you know we we obviously we had been
known we were going to host Noman for a
while but we kind of last minute decided
hey let's do it together in person
because I wanted to go see Joel's new
house anyway um and yeah dude it worked
out pretty well we said all right we've
got an hour to put together a studio for
this whole thing and naham got the uh
you know setups individualized again for
one person versus two and uh and it went
through so that was pretty great that
was
awesome um all right dude we're gonna do
a quick one today because it's a long
weekend we got some busy stuff going on
um so but I did want to go through a
couple things that I've been thinking
about lately um and one of them is
freaking Yan Carlson calling me out on
Twitter because I didn't know about the
question mark do syntax do you know
about the question mark do syntax I
didn't I mean I didn't know that Javas
supported this I've seen this in a lot
of other languages so I guess I'm not
surprised but I am a little surprised um
it's it's super interesting um it's uh
it like basically is like a if not null
right yeah yeah exactly it's a um
optional chaining operator um and I
think that this is mostly used when
you're like trying to figure out if
there's multiple layers of elements in
place like sub attributes um on an
object but it's also possible to use
this at in between a function name and
the you know sort of whatever these bad
boy always are the the the parentheses
that you use to uh call a function um
and so I I didn't wasn't aware of that
and I comment on this uh post on Twitter
I'm like oh wow I'm kind of surprised
this worked and then freaking Johan
Carlson comes in there and says I'm
surprised that you're surprised good sir
it's a valid operator and I'm like okay
listen here Johan I know you're
listening to this you know I bring you
on my my
podcast and now you're calling me out on
Twitter um no he's right I probably
should have known about that and I think
it's really useful for for anybody who's
dealing with wafts in any capacity um
because I think I think not a lot of
wafts are anticipating a question mark
and a DOT to be in between a function
name and the function call um
parenthesis so I think it's a good one
to be aware of yeah that that's a that's
super good one to have in your back
pocket and um speaking of waft bypasses
uh no WF is uh the new uh the new tool
from asset note so aset note
slubs uh launched this tool called noaf
PLS I I feel like it should be plz plz I
think you're stuck in 2012 bro I don't
know nobody says plz anymore does no one
say plz am I showing my Millennial here
yeah you're old you're old dude outdated
lovely thank you for that but is good
yeah this thing is awesome it um I mean
tldr is it all the different techniques
and stuff that uh were in the talk uh
for you know different methods and
bypasses to different waffs uh are
Incorporated within this tool to help
you bypass waffs you know so no W plus
and it's and it's all it's all pretty
simple too I mean all it is um I wrote
the kaido version for it um and
essentially what it does is it adds a
bunch of padding to your request so if
it's a you know URL encoded content type
then it just adds like a equals a a a a
you know jump like sometimes up to 100
megabytes of A's and then your actual
content right um but sometimes it's as
low as8 kilobytes that you'll need to to
bypass these wafts that are just like oh
8 kilobytes that's too big we can't
process that and then moves along um so
it was pretty easy to build in kaido it
doesn't have all the features you know
you got to go into the the workflow and
manually set the kilobyte size of
padding that you want but it should do
the job to bypass most wafts and I just
love the Simplicity of this whole
technique cuz it's just like all right
throw a bunch of garbage in there and
then the wa says uh oh I don't know what
to do with that go
ahead such a crazy technique I mean it's
like I mean it seems so simple but at
the same time you're like wow I can't
believe that works yeah yeah dude I'm
with you on that one um all right so
like I said we're gonna we're going to
move along pretty quickly today because
it's a tight weekend for us but um this
next one that I actually do I don't know
man maybe this needs a little bit more
discussion but uh I I did want to at
least shout it out um I am
d3d uh on Twitter tweeted out something
about a entire report being uh redacted
by a customer on bug crowd and I've also
seen this on hacker one as well where
your entire report will just get deleted
from hacker one and it won't be like
deleted deleted but it'll the whole
thing will be redacted and the 's just
no way to access your own vulner report
and I feel like this is pretty whack and
the explanations from the various
programs have been kind of a Miss I
think what what what are your thoughts
on this bad boy yeah I mean I don't want
to get into it too much um I think it's
certainly very interesting like that
they can do that I totally see why why
they might want to do that because like
it is their IP I guess right like um you
know the the vulnerability itself and
like all the information disclosed
within it
so it's a it's a tricky situation for
sure I don't know um you know at the end
of the day you are handing the
vulnerability over so if that's
something that you're concerned about
you can always just like keep a local
copy of all your reports um but yeah you
know nothing stops you from doing that
but uh yeah I mean the company does sort
of have the right to you know because
they they have full edit you know when
the report like goes into the program
like it's in their inbox they they could
control everything on the report they
can change the title they can do
whatever right so like um you know
there's some level of sort of ownership
over that yeah yeah I I hear that I just
think it's also a place for the hackers
to store their vulnerabilities and like
a a you know a history of what
vulnerabilities you found or like maybe
you want those um pieces of information
in there so you can go back later and
like check those techniques or maybe
even check for regressions right that's
a pretty common thing that we do is go
back look at all the reports we found
and then see if those if those fixes
that have been put in place have been un
undone and so you can get another
vulnerability so I think it's a little
tricky I think there's maybe a um a tool
opportunity here a uh a toport tunity so
to speak what I
called a to
opportunity a to opportunity a tool
opportunity that one man yeah well you
know I'm spinning on the Fly today so um
I I think it'd be cool to have a a tool
that just runs on a Cron job on on your
um on your VPS just make it super simple
all you do is give it the input uh like
access access token or API token for
hacker one or for bug crowd and then it
just pulls all your reports down and
creates a backup of them and uh it I
think that would be really valuable yeah
you can um you can export uh reports
pretty easily I believe yeah you can
that's true so it shouldn't be very hard
to code either but but then it can't be
like continuously updating because if
they go in and be and like redact it and
then you overwrite your you know normal
copy with a redacted copy then you're
kind of screwed so you kind of got to
know which one you've already pulled and
then only pull those
ones yeah yeah yeah yeah 100% yeah so I
think I think that would be cool I would
run that on my VPS um it does make your
VPS little bit more of a uh yeah it does
make your VPS a little bit more of a
Target though maybe I'll run that on
like a like a Cron job on my local
server at my house and just have it like
back up to like a a uh you know external
drive or something like that so it's not
out there on the internet that just kind
of gives me the ebgbs a little bit yeah
yeah totally yeah um all right man uh
let's see we got the sort of um recap
from Johan Carlson's uh xss challenge
which I think was pretty cool um or we
can go and talk about this u m bear
tweet um let's let's go into that one
because this one's kind of interesting
right take a look at this um this is a
tweet that Monon bear retweeted so it's
not even from him I just he just brought
it to my attention but the Tweet says
this uh there is a popular opinion bad
cores like Access Control out origin
star is unexploitable that's the the
popular opinion I think the browsers
won't send a cookie in this case um it
is
delusional which is or it is a delusion
is what it says um you can exploit it
with a Chrome cache feature one I just
love how strongly worded that is like
this is delusional um but two I I think
there's an interesting uh technique here
which is that he's saying that you can
exploit this with Chrome's cache feature
um and the the little infographic that
it says here is
um cores like Access Control origin star
may be useless at first sight
uh because you can't send cookies with
it but Chrome caches get responses
without the uh cash control no store
Header by default for two days and then
you can leak the response of this by
using force cach uh method um along with
with Fetch and then that will send the
if you know the the URL that was cached
you can send a request out you can force
it to use the cache and it will pull
that cached version back um and since it
has access control allower in Star it
will actually allow you to read that
response um which I think is pretty cool
but something makes me say that this got
fixed at some point did you did you ever
hear anything about
that I mean I'm not um enough of like a
web guy I I would consider myself like
when it comes to like the nitty-gritty
of this kind of stuff I I am my finger
is not on the pulse enough so I
definitely didn't um but uh it's super
interesting I mean these are like
like like I I feel like if I were to go
exploit an nexs nowadays I would hit so
many of these like weird things that be
like I would not even be able to like
compete yeah the access control the
course stuff I think is a little bit Tri
tricky sometimes but I want to say that
this actually now that I'm thinking
about it I want to say that this
technique is is fixed so I'm gonna I'm
gonna pause it and I'm going to go I'm
going to go check it right now hey guys
real quick I just wanted to give a shout
to the hacker content team they have
been absolutely killing it the past
couple months taking the content from
the podcast and condensing it down into
consumable social media posts whether it
be shorts or text posts or whatever
they've been rocking it so uh I just
wanted to give them a shout out and let
you know that they do all sorts of cyber
security content as well as social media
management they do technical blogs they
do uh comprehensive social media
management uh so if your organization
could benefit from any of those types of
services make sure you head over to
hacker content.com drop them a line and
mention the podcast when you do to get
your first month of cyber security
content marketing services for free all
right that's it let's get back to the
Pod all right dude I investigated that
real quick and actually I knew that that
sounded familiar to me when I put the
notes in the dock yeah it is fixed um
but I really I thought it was a really
interesting exploit when it first came
out in or when I first saw it it was
first introduced with it a little bit
earlier on and I think that there are
probably other opportunities like that
with Force Cash in place um um but I
just wanted to also kind of put that out
there as well that this it does not
appear that this technique works at
least with my my current um setup that I
I want well if I can throw a little
Shameless plug in here you know we have
this channel called intent to ship uh
that's uh true it's available to our
critical thinkers and I feel like
something like this would probably show
up in there if it were to change so um
if you're a subscriber uh on our Discord
and you're one of the critical thinkers
then you'll have access to this and
you'll probably know ahead of time yeah
yeah man I wish I had that Discord
Channel whenever I uh whenever they fix
this in the first place because I would
have I would have been able to keep up
to date with that also I will say though
that um we only are currently pulling
the stuff for um blink in there but
there's also uh the rendering engine
that um Firefox uses which I believe is
called gecko or something like that yeah
something like that so I'm I'm gonna
update that bot as well soon to include
the stuff from gecko so that we can stay
on top of all that as well um you know
for what whatever measley share of users
Firefox represents at this point yeah
yeah what it like 2% or something yeah
something like that yeah um all right so
a couple more things I wanted to go
through here um the the next one okay
dude did you see uh freaking Johan's
CTF with the sandbox frame no no I
didn't I didn't it was It was kind of
crazy actually dude I was looking at it
for a while and there's a couple pieces
to it one of them is like a CSP bypass
it utilizes the the fact that like you
can redirect from a domain that is like
if you have a path-based um CSP uh in
place for script source so let's say you
whitelist like technog geek. okay
JavaScript right and a a user can
actually host JavaScript at technog
geek. bad JavaScript or whatever if you
can make a redirect from okay JavaScript
to bad JavaScript then it will trust
that redirection um okay and so that was
one of the cool things one of the cool
hacks that he had in place for that CTF
but but the one that he really that
really kind of blew my mind was this
whole concept of essentially you can
escape a Sandbox inside of an eye frame
um uh and leak the base URI uh of the
top level frame with no relationship to
that that frame you know with with no
like allow same origin or anything like
that and this sandboxing thing sort of
works by uh you know defining a null
origin for that frame and then trust
same origin policy to sort of um to sort
of make sure that you can't access the
data in a different frame but uh what
Yan figured out was when a source Doc is
used in iframe in conjunction with that
sandbox that you can access the
document. base URI property and what
that will do is it will give you the um
the URI that is associated with uh this
the top level document not the sandbox
document um because of the Source doc I
I think being different than the actual
Source super interesting in the iframe
yeah and so essentially what you could
do is you could have a Sandbox I frame
origin null no ability to do anything
besides run scripts and you can um leak
the top you know window location hre of
the top um top frame which will lead to
a bunch of really cool bugs I think but
it sounds most impactful in in an
environment where you can like
essentially land an ooth code on that
top level um uh path and then go from
your sandboxed if frame up and grab that
oath code and exfiltrate it super super
cool that's really interesting I I I
love these little uh these little mini
ctfs that keep coming out um the like
acccess challenges and stuff um yeah
like I feel like they disappeared for a
while but it's good it hones your skills
you know they're real world problems a
lot of the time like this almost
certainly came from a real vulnerability
that he had to exploit and he was
sitting there he was like hm I wonder
how many other people can exploit this
exactly well I'm I'm also interested
because it's like um frame source iframe
source doc which is the you know
alternative to a source for an iframe
you can provide a source Doc and
actually just write the HTML code right
directly inside the attribute um I feel
like it's a pretty rare thing to see but
I could also see this happening a lot in
like um e-commerce environments or
something like that where you need to be
able to provide some uh customization to
the environment uh while still
actually not letting the user get access
to like credit card data and stuff like
that um so I think there's lots of
applications for this um how often
Source Doc is actually used I I can't
say though because I I've pretty much
mostly just seen the source attribute
used if you're defining an iframe yeah
yeah yeah I think it's easier to do it
that way too because then you don't have
to worry about like B 64 encoding the
whole thing or like you know sticking it
inside the source doc um so it's a
little bit of a niche thing but that's
that's what we're all about here these
sort of Niche edge cases so if you guys
see
um uh Source doc defined instead of
Source on an ier make sure you keep this
trick in mind yeah yeah
absolutely um all right dude let's see
let's take a look at some of these other
ones here um
okay this one is exciting okay let me
just let me just let me just say let me
just say this one okay um there was a uh
a block post that I think we've talked
about a little bit before um that came
out iframe and window.open um it was
from blog. Huli
dotw and um I read through a lot of it
and I was a little bit disappointed to
see that there was a technique that had
been sort of uh you know cards close to
the chest wasn't really talking about
this one quite as much um that got
disclosed there so I figed all right let
me just go ahead and and talk about it
um and that technique is
once again regarding sandbox iframes um
and essentially what happens here Joel
is when you define a Sandbox iframe you
can def Define a set of like sandbox
attributes associated with it right you
can just say like all right allow script
allow popup allow modal allow same
origin you've got all these like options
right yep um what's really cool is that
if you do a window. open from that if
that sandbox if frame that window that
results in you know that that pops up in
your browser in a new tab that that bad
boy will also have those same properties
um that the sandbox iframe has so then
you get into this weird scenario where I
can define an i frame on my page that
that has the sandbox attributes and you
click a button on there and it opens up
a new tab on jo.com and now joel. comom
has those and my cookies are sent to to
joe.com everything it's like a full top
level nav but the origin of that page is
set to
null so it's not set to nor the normal
like top level jo.com thing so if I were
to try to access the source of that page
from a um or or communicate with that
page from another null null origin
iframe then you could do Communications
if the um if the post message Handler or
whatever you're you're working with here
checks window. origin or origin if it
says event. origin so event being the
post message message that's being sent
equals equal window. origin which is a
very common code pattern um to check
whether the message is coming from the
current page that you're on or not um
then it will allow communication but
what we can do now is we can change that
origin on on jo.com or bank.com or
whatever to n yeah and then communicate
with that iframe from another null
origin if frame um that's really
interesting that's a really interesting
technique and it still works it does
still works it's fix now oh okay no it
it works I mean I think it's just a
function
it works yeah yeah dude I was I was kind
of like kept on looking for
opportunities to use it and I had an
opportunity one time where it was going
to work out so good and there was just
this one little like teeny tiny
mitigating Factor where I couldn't get
it to to actually work um but because it
is inside of a Sandbox iframe you have a
bunch of other restrictions so it's not
like it doesn't like break the whole
internet but um it will allow because
you can't make requests out you know you
can't do a bunch of other stuff because
of the sandbox but um what you can do is
you can access any data that's loaded
onto that page so if you're able to like
open up a page that says hello Joel or
whatever um with authorized user since
your cookies were sent with that
original top level navigation um you can
actually leak the data that's on that
page um and exfiltrate it out so dang
definitely another another cool
technique that's a cool bug man I I
can't I can't recommend enough going to
this you know blog. toi or Huli dotw and
reading this blog post it's a really
high quality one if you want to
understand same origin policy and the
ways that frames communicate heck yeah
yeah yeah it's a good one man um all
right I know I know uh we've got a
little bit only got a little bit longer
today um let me look at some of these
other ones okay do you want let me give
you an option here because we can't get
through all these um do you want to have
me talk about
a plugin a chrome plugin that I think
really needs more attention or do you
want me to talk about a technique that
really you know what I'm gonna go with
the the second one it's more in line
with the topic everybody I'm just going
to say this go check out Dom logger PP
if you haven't already that is going to
be a very pivotal tool I think in the
future of web of client web security
never I hav't heard of that thing and
it's looks pretty crazy man it's pretty
awesome itow it allows you to do your D
your due diligence on Cent side stuff
very well
um Joel let me let me let me run you run
this last one by you okay so this
concept iframe hijacking I think is
really consistent with the stuff that
we're talking about here and it hasn't
we've talked about it I think once
before on the Pod but we haven't talked
about it super thoroughly um and it's
this concept okay you you have a page
like for example an oath flow that will
do a window do open right it's going to
pop up like a little box or something
like that that that you know click prove
or whatever blahy blahy blah right and
then um it's going to communicate from
that little box back to the the main
page that opened it up pretty common
flow right yep yeah you see it all over
the place
yeah here's the thing you can hijack
that little box um and the way you do
that is if the the page that pop does
the window dot open if it supplies the
name of the frame that uh it will be
opening that up in which most of the
time they do uh then what you can do is
you can create a page or an if frame on
your attacker controlled
page and you can uh put that iframe to
be the same origin of the page that will
be uh opening up the the new popup so if
it's on like you know login.
whatever.com then you set it to like
login. whatever.com 44 or something like
that something that's if framable you
know you want to try to find maybe it's
like an icon or something and they
forgot the uh you know if frame not
allowed uh or x-frame options header um
and you can embed it into your page you
set it to that okay and then you name
that iframe the name of the window that
they're going to window. open on this
other page and so what what's going to
happen when they click on the link in in
the page that you want to attack is it
will say it'll look through the tab
group and it'll say hey is there any
frame that exists in our little like
circle of frames here that has this name
and if so I'm going to open into that
and so what it does is it identifies the
frame that you set up in your page and
it will actually open up that that
website into that frame okay so now you
now it it says okay I've just opened up
this page you know the user is going to
be like authorizing stuff blah blah blah
I'm going to trust that that popup that
happened right um but really it wasn't a
popup it went to that iframe now since
we put that iframe in our own page we
can redirect that iframe to whatever we
want we can redirect it to an attacker
controlled page do you get a window
reference back from that too you do yeah
because it's you know you created the if
frame so you can go ahead and and and
you know everything looks fine and dandy
to the to the victim side where they did
the window dot open and since you have
the I frame on your page you can easily
get a window reference through that um
and so uh then you know you can redirect
that page to a malicious page you can um
you can just bypass the whole flow and
inject your attacker controlled
credentials there right A lot of times
what will happen is they'll do like an
off call back to a specific page and
then there will be data in the hash and
it'll because it'll be same origin it'll
it'll reach in and grab that data well
you can just redirect it to what the
same origin and then inject your own
data in the hash and then now you're
controlling the flow of the application
um and I call this bad boy frame
hijacking um I think it's a lot of
things are vulnerable to this um and the
main takeaway here is make sure whenever
you see a new a popup happening or some
change happening in an if frame look to
see the window. open call that's that's
doing it and check the name on that
because if it is using a name that is
guessable then you may be able to hijack
that iframe and gain control of the flow
in that specific
scenario that's really really
interesting does all that make sense I
know I kind of sounded like that guy
with like the strings and like the map
you
know yeah I know I think I followed you
though yeah that that's that's pretty
freaking sweet um yeah just have it's
it's so it's a browser Behavior though
like it is and it's only in
Chrome okay that's super interest so if
you so you can have two windows with the
same name in Firefox um you know it
seems like that's the case right because
in Firefox it doesn't open it up and the
window. open would then trigger and open
up a new window um and I don't know why
it doesn't work in Firefox because
they're in the same tab group it seems
like that should be compliant with the
spec but maybe they make some sort of
differentiation because you know your
frame is sort of sandwiched in between
the two and it's I don't know it just
doesn't work in Firefox for some reason
yeah that's super weird also it also
doesn't work in Incognito tab in Chrome
which is weird um so there's there's
some weird restrictions that are going
on there
huh huh I guess I wonder if it's just
because of the anti-tracking stuff the
anti-tracking stuff has been getting in
the way a lot lately I don't know what
Chrome did recently with that but there
anytime there's a use of an eye frame
something weird is happening that's
super weird yeah all right man that's
pretty much all I had for today um I
won't go into the whole sh about the um
Dom logger PP but it's a really cool
thing so definitely go check it out you
got anything else you wanted to shout
before we move along I think that's it
man all right sweet it'll be it'll be a
short one today but you know we're
staying consistent for you guys the the
listeners even though it's a busy week
so um hopefully you guys get a lot out
of this whole iframe mess that we just
got today yeah lots of new tools Nots
lots of new techniques to to dig into in
your free time indeed indeed in the time
that you are spending not listening to
this episode of critical thinking go and
read that that blog post about frames
and window.open we'll link down
absolutely absolutely peace guys
peace and that's a wrap on this episode
of critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ctbb Dosh
show/ Discord join the Discord there's
lots of great conversations and chats
going on over there and if you want to
support the show there's the Discord
subscriber tiers which give you access
to master classes amas hack along alongs
exclusive scripts and an exclusive chat
Channel with us we'll see you there